Three buddies in Vietnam. Two survived. Only one is really alive.
Jacknife is a drama, war film directed by David Hugh Jones.
A conflict develops between a troubled Vietnam veteran and the sister he lives with when she becomes
involved romantically with the army buddy who reminds him of the tragic battle they both survived.
Joseph 'Jacknife' Megessey, played by Robert De Niro.
Martha Flannigan, played by Kathy Baker.
David 'High School' Flannigan, played by Ed Harris.
Depot Mechanic, played by Ivar Brogger.
Tiny, played by Jordan Lund.
Jake, Veteran Encounter Group Leader, played by Charles S. Dutton.
Jacknife is a 1989 American film directed by David Jones and
starring Robert De Niro, Ed Harris and Kathy Baker.
The film focuses on a complex tension between
people in a close family relationship.
Stephen Metcalfe, on whose play Strange Snow (1982) the
film is based, wrote the screenplay.
Harris was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for his performance.
The tone is emotional.